Kartavya Saini

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kartavya99/ | GitHub: https://github.com/kartavya99 | Portfolio: https://kartavya99.github.io/react-portfolio/

Phone: +61 410742021 | Email: kartavyas@gmail.com | Melbourne, AU

SUMMARY:

Full stack web developer leveraging a background in sales and marketing to provide the best user experience for web application development. Obtained a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Monash University's intensive 24-week coding boot camp. Adaptive problem-solver who loves to develop apps with focus on mobile-first design and development. Strengths in adaptability, detail-orientation, creativity, communication, problem-solving, teamwork, time-management, leadership, perseverance, and building projects from concept to completion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages:

JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Application:

React, TDD, MongoDB, MySQL, MVC, Third Party APis, Object Oriented Programming/Design(OOP), Object Relational Programming (ORM), Progressive Web Applications (PWA), Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, JSON, BootStrap

Tools:

Git, Heroku, MS Office.

Productivity:

Slack, Microsoft Office Suits, Zoom

PROJECTS:

Ecommerce-website | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- **Summary:** A full stack web application build with MERN stack, where business can list their products for marketing and advertising purpose
- Tools: MongoDb, Express, React, NodeJs

Together Fitness | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- <u>Summary</u>: Using Together Fitness users can search through the list of workouts and can choose the workout with its location plus users can create workout
- <u>Tools</u>: Node.js, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, JAWSDB, Heroku, Query, Bootstrap, Dotenv, BCrypt Hash Password, Geolocation API, Google Place API

Search it | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- **Summary:** A search based web application which will allow the user to gain information in the form of videos and data
- Tools: YouTube API, Wikipedia API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Tech Blog | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- **Summary:** Platform for users to create different posts, updated and delete. User can also add and comments to posts as well. User Authentication is used for security purpose as well.
- Tools: JavaScript, Node, Express, Sequelize, mysql2

EXPERIENCE:

Dnata Catering, Melbourne, AU -Domestic Consolidator **January 2022 – PRESENT**

- Responsible for ensuring in-flight meals for Qantas domestic flights
- Achieved Quality and Quantity standards as per flight requirements.

Ultra Scrap Metal, Melbourne, AU - Director **June 2017 -August 2020**

- Built a scrap metal trading business specialized in different Stainless Steel grades.
- Succeeded in purchasing container loads from different scrap yards and supplying to foundries and mills in India.

TNT Express NZ ltd, Auckland, NZ - Account Manager July 2015- Jan 2017

- Managed geographical territory worth \$4 million NZD per annum.
- Enhanced customer base of geographical territory worth \$4 million NZD per annum by up selling, cross selling or acquiring new business.

EDUCATION:

Monash University, Melbourne - Full-Stack Web Development Certificate February 2022 - August 2022 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills. Link to certificate - link

Alliance Francaise, India- Diploma in French language March 2004 - June 2006 French language

Gujarat University, India- Bachelor of Commerce June 2000 -April 2003 Advance Accounting and Auditing